Welcome into Jags AM Kani Stevens here.
Brian Ston, John Oer with me today after
an eventful weekend. It was draft
weekend here in Duvall and it was a
little bit different than it normally
goes because there was no first round
picked but still eventful nonetheless.
So, let's get into our big things today.
And our first big thing is hurry up and
wait. As mentioned, there was no first
round pick, but it's a familiar spot for
GM James Gladstone, who previously
worked in LA. They're used to not having
first round picks, but still finding
some talent later in the draft. I
certainly think you can find quality
players at a ton of different intervals
and we certainly had success towards the
latter half and uh latter portion of
drafts and also undrafted college free
agency in Los Angeles uh specifically at
the linebacker position. Uh but
nonetheless, I think that instincts are
certainly going to be something that re
supreme in that space knowing that a lot
happens fast and in the specific
interest of of Parker uh that stands out
in a real way.
Ryan, we thought maybe they'd go
linebacker early. There was a lot of
predictions. They definitely didn't do
anything of what we thought they were
going to do, but James Gladstone still
thinks he can get some serious
contributors from this chunk of players.
>> Well, and he referenced the Rams, and I
think we did in our instant analysis
several times over the course of the
weekend. Listen, the litany, the laundry
list of players uh around the league who
were either second or third day draft
picks or undrafted rookie free agents
who've made it and had significant
careers is significant. I They needed a
tight end. They took two. You know, they
needed a safety. They found one. They
needed edge players. They found a
couple. They knew what their list was.
They were very specific in what they
were looking for. And we've talked a lot
about it. We will continue to talk a lot
about it. They feel really good about
finding guys that fit their system. Did
they find all pros? I mean, those are
hard enough to find anywhere in the
draft, but did they find good football
players? They think so.
>> Yeah. If you want some insight into
this, uh, James Gladston's on the ozone
pod this week, he actually talked about
their early draft strategy. Um, and it
really was they had efforts to move up.
They had areas that they made calls to
move up into, but they had very specific
parameters that they were going to
follow to be in that. And that's why he
used the word strategically bold. Uh
sometimes when a GM doesn't make a pick,
people think, oh, well, he wasn't
aggressive. Well, you know, you can be
aggressive, but you don't want to be
stupid. So the idea was to see if it was
possible to move up and then if you if
they didn't then the idea was to have
multiple picks late in the round to give
themselves percentage chances of
succeeding where your percentages are a
little better up top. But that's the
strategy they used at the Rams and that
they used here this weekend. Let's go to
our next big thing which as you
mentioned is strategically bold. James
Gladstone talked about when they make
those decisions they're not just going
with maybe who is always the highest
ranking but who's going to fit in here.
you know, we're not going to invite
anybody into this building uh who isn't
a strong match for it. And you know, the
the idea that those that we have uh are
in fact built to thrive and be the best
versions of themselves because of the
the environment and and that alignment
with what they're actually built of and
made of, I think, is uh is really clear
in this crop.
John, when we look at back at the draft,
the Jaguars picking a tight end early,
maybe none of us really predicted that
happening, but it did kick off a huge
run of tight ends. And when you're
looking at where they're picking and
where their picks are available to them,
it does make sense when you look back at
it like that.
>> Well, they really liked uh Nate Boer
Kercher, I think I'm saying his name
right.
Um, so
there's a little bit in the draft here
of sometimes people analyze it from the
big picture whereas teams have to look
at specifics. They liked him at 56. Um,
could they have gotten him at 70? Maybe.
Were they going to get him at 88?
Probably not. So, you got to take your
guy when you take your guy. And Brian
Kai's exactly right. You could tell by
the way of the draft. I don't think
people before the draft when they were
pre-analyzing it realized that there was
going to be this tight end demand. If
you wanted your guy, you were going to
have to take it because they went off
the board fast after after the Jaguars
picked at 56.
>> Yeah. There weren't many of them. There
were two that went in front of where the
Jaguars picked at 56. But then there was
a group of guys that all sort of had the
same qualities. Now you you get to
choose the one that fits you best.
Whether we're talking about the fit in
the locker room, whether it's you put
value on really long arms and really big
hands, right? Whatever it is that you
value, John, you and I have covered this
K. You covered the Patriots. All those
years that the Patriots were winning,
they were taking guys that other teams
didn't necessarily value as high as they
did. Why? Well, because Bellich had the
Patriot way. and the things that they
valued were very specific to their
roster with Tom Brady on it and what he
could overcome. Their salary cap with
heavy with stars. Same thing with the
Steelers back in the '90s. They were
able to draft from a completely
different paradigm because they were one
of the few three four teams back then.
So they would take a 6'3 295 lb
defensive tackle because they played it
differently. Each team has what they
think is important for them, which
adjusts where you rank a player and how
it fits what you want.
>> Yeah. And Kai, there's all this talk
about how, you know, uh, Nate, the
second round pick with a fifth round.
Forget that. Uh, there were teams that
were going to take him in the second
round, the Jaguars hadn't. So, uh, a lot
of what you read and feel in the in the,
uh, interweb, Kai, uh, take with a grain
of salt. The interwebs can't always be
trusted. Our final big thing today is
going to be roster spots with 10 new uh
additions via the draft and then over a
dozen additions via undrafted free
agents. Brian, this roster might look a
lot different in the upcoming season
because it's a it's important to mention
this is only the second season for this
current administration. They're still
trying to get their guys in there.
>> Yeah, I said this to a couple different
people over the weekend. It was so
impressive what they did last year going
from 4-3 to 13-4
with largely the previous year's roster.
They added a few guys here and there.
Now they have a chance to bring their
own guys in. And John Kais, you look at
the roster turnover on average, it's
about 30% yeartoyear. So you're going to
lean towards the guys that you drafted
to fit your specific needs. And I would
imagine that
12 14 of these guys are going to be on
the roster.
>> Yeah, I'd say uh that number is probably
accurate. And you also got to remember
now the whole idea of a 53 in the NFL is
a little bit anticated. Uh you're 16
guys on the practice squad figure in
you're really carrying about 69 and four
or five of those guys in the practice
squad are coming up and into your
roster. So I got emails for the draft
guy. Oh, can they have 11 picks? Can 11
guys make this team? Absolutely. And I'm
with Brian. I would expect 10, 11, 12
guys out of this draft class. And as you
said, couple it with last year. Now
you're at 27, 28 guys that this regime
has brought in as young rookies, uh, a
life comes at you fast and rosters
change fast in the NFL.
>> Absolutely. More changes to come. Stay
with us here on Jags AM though. We're
going to talk about every single player
they picked in this draft over the
weekend.
>> Yes. Whatever.
>> One of the big guys, Emanuel Pragon,
there with his family celebrating. I
love those videos. Um, we're going to
release some of the phone calls, I
think, today. And it's just so cool to
obviously have kind of be sharing that
moment with them and their dreams being
realized.
>> Did you see the size of that guy's arms?
I mean, we heard he's big, but my
goodness,
>> we'll see. He's It's going to be uh He
told me his strategy for protecting a
quarterback is giving them as much time
as they need. And if they want to sit on
Trevor wants to sit on the toilet back
there, he said he'll have time to do
that. I said,
>> "That's good." You like draft day.
They're at their most honest.
>> Absolutely. Um let's take a look at um
we have a full screen, I think, of all
the picks. There's 10 overall. They had
11 picks going into the day. fairly um
decent split. Five offense, five
defense, a couple of tight ends.
Obviously, we'll talk about that. Um
some big guys, defensive tackle,
offensive line, and then a little bit
later on some edge rushers, wide
receivers. It's a mix of everything. A
lot of guys that contribute on special
teams, a lot of these guys captains of
their teams, um five, six years in
college, some of these guys experience
coming in ready to play. Let's talk a
little bit about the tight ends because
obviously Nate Burkasher going early and
that run of tight ends that we talked
about and then everyone's like, "Oh, we
took a blocking tight end so early, but
then you know they add another tight end
a little bit later." So, where we've
heard a little bit from them, but it
sounds like they want to kind of run
with two tight ends and that's where
this is coming in.
>> Well, and we talked about the Rams all
weekend long and and the connection
between Liam Cole and Shawn McVey. I
also remember an LA connection when
Mercedes Lewis was this team's draft
choice in 2006. He caught 96 passes his
senior year at UCLA, but he came in and
became a blocking tight end early in his
career. And that's because the Jaguars
love the size and the length that he
had. You see this guy can do a lot of
different things when you watch the
tape. How they intend to use him is how
they intend to use him. You can't
necessarily, and they don't, just look
at what he did and say, "Well, that's
all he can be." Clearly, he's a guy who
moves. He's got length. There's a shot
of a ball in the end zone that he
catches where he's having to avoid a
defender. I wouldn't make the mistake of
saying he was a 19 catch guy and say
he's only going to be a blocking tight
end cuz we've seen it flip in this
league, John.
>> Yeah, they don't believe that's what he
is. Um, and remember, everybody like
raised their eyebrows of Brenton Strange
and he's one of the best three players
on this team.
>> Yeah.
>> The tight end is interesting. If you
want a really good synopsis of it, uh,
uh, Bucky Brooks in a story that I'm
writing, I think for today has a really
good quote explaining exactly what teams
are doing. Essentially, as teams, as as
defenses play more nickel and and play
more multi-defensive back defenses, uh,
teams are wanting to go to more tight
ends because you can either run on it or
the tight ends give them fits because
it's designed to stop receiver routes.
That's the simple version of it. Uh but
that's the way uh teams are going. And
in order to take advantage of that, they
had to pivot a little bit. Hard to go
get to free agent tight ends to uh to
fill that because everybody's keeping
their tight ends. So the way to do it
was the draft. It's an interesting move,
but you saw the league trending toward
that. As soon as the Jaguars drafted,
there was an amaz I think it was nine on
the first two days. Um, and then there
were four or five more in round four.
Uh, this was a thirst for tight ends.
>> And we saw what the Rams did to the rest
of the league. I mean, they're one of
the best teams in football all year.
Matthew Stafford was the MVP with 46
touchdowns. 17 touchdowns went to his
tight ends. And Kai, they they had 11
catches for more than 100 yards and a
touchdown against the Jaguars in London.
And you could just see the Jaguars
couldn't match up with a bunch of these
6'5, 6'6 tight ends, none of whom went
to the Pro Bowl, but all of them were
contributors to one of the most
explosive offenses in the game.
>> And having that ability to kind of have
breakout games, we didn't touch on it
fully, but Tanner Kosil has those
touchdowns. If you're worried about
saying Borcasher doesn't have the
touchdowns, Kosil does. So having both
of those skills plus what Brent Strange
brings to the field, it feels like it's
giving them a lot more options on
offense. that I'm sure Liam Cohen loves
extra options on.
>> Well, that's that's the whole key. Last
year, and I think Liam said it maybe to
you or on the podium when they when
Brenton got injured last year, uh they
had three losses. I think two of them or
three of them were when he was out. Uh
it was a significant drop in the offense
and they knew that if they want to be
able to lean into this scheme a little
bit, you can't just have have Brentton
Strange. It's not like they're going to
come out and only be in that formation.
But last year, they couldn't run those
things effectively that they saw other
teams were able to take advantages of
defenses with. And look, if you like
Liam, which all Jaguars fans should, you
got to know that if there's something
going on with defenses that can be taken
advantage of, he's going to want to get
to that. So, I think this this is what
that was about.
>> They lost to Seattle, Los Angeles, and
Houston without Breton. And that Houston
game in particular in the fourth quarter
where they couldn't get a first down,
you have to think that one of the
quarterback's favorite targets would
have helped them move the chains.
Absolutely. Let's talk about a little
bit about uh some of the big guys.
Albert Regis out of Texas A&M defensive
tackle and then Emanuel Pregnon who we
saw celebrating um a offensive lineman
out of Oregon. And uh Regis is we we
talked right we were like hey we need
defensive tackle obviously more presence
inside and I think what they like about
him is some versatility to then move
some other pieces around. Well, and this
is also a strategic pick for the future
of the franchise because Devon Hamilton
is in the final year of his contract.
So, you're always looking to find guys
for depth and quality, but also for the
future, and he's a second, pardon me, a
third round pick, and you expect a guy
who's a third round pick to be capable
of coming in and being a starter. There
were a couple of selections that they
made over the weekend where you could
see strategically how they were setting
themselves up to be able to fill gaps
when they lose players to either
retirement or free agency.
>> Yeah, my guess I think Devon will be
here for a little longer than that, but
um I think the key here with Regis, this
was a draft that it was very difficult
to find pass rush at the defensive
tackle position. His stats don't say
he's a pass rusher, but when you listen
to people talk about him, he's got
quickness. He's got penetration ability.
Um, I don't know that he's going to be
an Aaron Donald, a 12 sack pass rusher.
Those guys are very, very rare, but I
think they had to look in this draft for
for sort of hidden guys who could get
some penetration uh that maybe everybody
else didn't think could get penetration.
Uh, so I think they think there's some
ability there with this guy to do that.
And I feel like at least the last couple
of years, a lot of some of the issues
with the pass rushes, no penetration in
the middle is is making it more
difficult for for them to keep the edge
and and that'll only help everybody else
out, right? It's a team sport at the end
of the day. And we talk about when you
can get a little push from from inside,
that's only going to help Josh Hines and
Trayvon Walker on the outside.
>> If the quarterback can't step up, he has
to choose 41 or 44. Which one can I
beat?
>> Um, Emanuel Pregnon coming out of Oregon
can never have enough linemen. And I
knew Tony wasn't going to let us get out
of the weekend without adding um to the
offensive line, but another big body and
and it's uh it when it comes to linemen,
obviously have to get them in here and
see where they are, but just energy-wise
feels like he's on the right page.
>> Well, it uh
lineman
ideally, unless they're first rounders,
you don't want them playing early. You
love to have them have time to develop.
Right now they have Milm and Pregnon who
who they have brought in who you could
easily see being the starting guards for
this team from 27 forward and I think
Milo might be starter this year. So uh
if there was a guy who was sort of the
consensus uh why did he go so low guy in
this Jaguars draft it's pregnant. A lot
of people like him and he certainly has
the traits to make you think that he
could uh it it's hard to change an
entire offensive line on the fly. They
started to do it last year. You can see
the direction that they want to go with
this pick.
>> Ken, he's a left guard, right? You talk
to people, you you told that he is
primarily a left side player. And go
back to the contracts and the roster.
You've got Ezra Klein Ezra Klein Ezric
Cleveland who's going into the final
year of his deal. So you need a young
body that can compete this year and
eventually take over. And when you look
at it, you got Anton Harrison, you got
Wyatt Milm, Jonah Manheim is a guy that
they have some affection for that they
think can become a player. And now you
plug in Emanuel Pregnon, you feel pretty
good, especially with Cole coming back
from his injury of having your offensive
line of the future in place perhaps this
year.
>> The offensive line's just such an injury
plagued position, too. you can really I
mean I can't remember a season where any
team I've covered made it through with
the exact same five starting five the
entire year without any injury. So it's
definitely a position where you want to
have that flexibility
>> and you have eight who have started
coming back on the line that doesn't
include mil or pregnant. So, if you're
wondering how you keep a group
replenished, how you bring along depth
behind an already functioning group, uh,
they've clearly got their system in
place at linebacker. We see how they're
going to try to approach this.
>> They've got a really good coaching
staff, too. They got the most out of
players last year. I mean, Trevor
Lawrence, Anton Harrison, um, Devin
Lloyd, Antonio Johnson, I mean, you go
down the list. Brettton Strange, Parker
Washington, they get the most out of
these guys. They got more out of them
than the previous staff did. And so from
that perspective, you've got these young
guys and you feel good about their
ability to develop them the right way.
>> As we go a little bit later in the
draft, um two wide receivers and couple
edge players and a safety. Um Jaylen
Husky, a safety out of Maryland. I know,
uh coach Campanelli talking to me about
it. Uh first thing he said, he's like,
"He's a hitter." That's all you want to
hear from defensive coach. He couldn't
be more excited about it. Um but adding
some depth to a position we feel like is
pretty well staffed at this point but
was really plagued by injury last year.
>> Well the safety position um
he's depth but the way they play safety
around here they like to play three
right and uh you have Antonio Johnson
you have Eric Murray and you have Caleb
Ransaw coming back but that's three and
now if you get an injury Rayon Lane and
Husky are both guys who can play. So,
uh, I think this at some I I apologize
for that. Um, this is a guy who at some
point will be on the field this year.
>> Well, if you're going to play against
more tight end,
>> if you're going to see three tight ends,
you're going to need more safeties,
right? If that's the trend in the league
on offense to have more tight ends,
you're going to want bigger safeties who
can match up better with tight ends than
perhaps linebackers.
>> And this might be your guy. He not only
is bigger, hits interceptions, he's a
bit of a ball hawk as well. He's had a
good amount of interceptions during his
uh college career and we all know they
like to take the ball away.
>> And Antonio Johnson's going into the
final year of his deal.
>> Yes,
>> that was Jay Husky on the phone said he
was ready to go.
>> He said he want talk about him more.
Yeah, absolutely. Um who are some of the
other guys that you're kind of looking
at later? I mean, obviously we don't
know a ton of them until they get in
here and then there's some of the
lesserk known guys, but any names stand
out to you?
>> Well, I listen Wesley Williams. I
watched your interview with him and was
just captivated by his intensity. Um the
way that he is a gifted communicator,
right? He's a duke uh with a degree in
public policy and headed to law school
afterwards, but is a guy who John, they
can do a lot of interesting things with
him. They can put him outside and move
Trayvon inside. He's built I mean I saw
a video of him squatting in the Duke
locker room with his teammates around
him. He's strong enough that you can put
him inside with Trayvon perhaps and have
two of those undersized, quick, strong
pass rushers and and be able to do
something else on the outside. I mean, I
just I think he's a chess piece and and
I'm excited about seeing what he brings
to the table. Well, James Gladstone
likes talking about at bats late in the
draft and it feels like between Strale
Green, uh, Wesley Williams, you've got
some at bats now outside defensive end
where, okay, let's see who's ready.
Let's see who can give us something. Uh,
the wide receivers are interesting. Uh,
CJ Williams and Josh Cameron. Uh, one of
Hookah Nua's superpowers is strength.
you know, uh, very hard to bring down.
Uh, Josh Cameron squats, what is it?
528.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
>> you can do that, John. Right.
>> Well, if if I do it 528 times. Yes. Um,
divided up.
>> So, but I do think that that is
something that uh, you know, Gladstone
was in LA and certainly was there when
he saw Puka developing. So, um, I think
that sort of correlation, you're looking
for traits in the sixth and seventh
round. Uh to me that was probably a
trait they saw with this guy and say,
"Well, let's see if that can translate a
little bit to how the league's being or
how the game is being played right now."
>> I think the roster was pretty good. We
all would agree with that. That was why
they didn't have to go for need. I'm
sorry, a a glaring need, right?
>> You start looking at these guys and what
they bring to the table and you realize
that they have restocked the cupboard
with guys now developmental, sure, but
we just talked about how the coaching
staff does a good job with that. how
they have filled some gaps and given
themselves a level of depth in
competition that makes everyone around
them better, makes the roster, makes
training camp, makes the preseason more
competitive, and that's always good for
a football team.
>> All right, we talked about the draft
picks and we talked about being
strategically bold. Coming up, we're
going to go over some of these other
draft terms that came up over the
weekend.
the players make up his personal
character, his football character, and
uh continuing to try to bring in those
type of players and to add uh to the
culture in the locker room and getting
guys that are super competitive that
love football, that love to compete and
the process that goes along with it. So,
it's always at the forefront of every
pick that we make and um you know,
you're you're trying to challenge the
locker room, challenge it with both both
on the field and off the field.
>> That was my uh post-draft interview with
Liam Cohen and he's filling me in on
Duvall DNA. That was a term we heard
throughout the entire weekend. What does
that mean? Obviously, they're trying to
get culture fits in here right now, but
it's only the second year, the second
draft that they've had. So, they're not
going to bring in anybody that's not
going to help this team get to the point
where they want to be in terms of
setting that culture, being tough, being
physical, and I feel like that was a
focus for all of these players that you
brought in. I don't think anybody is um
not willing to make a block or
participate on special teams. These are
all guys that will do whatever they need
to do to be on the football field.
>> Listen, this is just a feeling. Um I I
can't back it up with anything. Just my,
you know, visceral observation. These
guys are all on the same page. Tony,
Liam, and James know exactly what they
want. I I didn't feel that with the
administration before. I I don't think I
felt that since there was one voice in
this building in Tom Coughlin back in
the day. There, Listen, there there can
be disagreements on players and
positions and things like that. But they
know exactly what they want. they
communicate on such a shared level,
right, that they know the kind of player
that they that they hope to bring in
here. Maybe that's why I trust them so
much because they're so consistent in
their approach in the way that they go
about gathering the information and and
and trying to create this environment
where everybody feels like they can
speak their mind. What was the word that
we heard? Authentic. They wanted
authentic
>> information.
>> Information. Um, but man, when he's
there talking, I feel like I'm listening
to Gladstone or Belli and they are
defined as to the type of player. Kind
of like we talked about earlier, the
Bradyled
>> Patriots were the Bellich led Patriots
were and the Steelers have always been.
It's good to have that sort of
definition.
>> Yeah. And James talked a lot about this
on the pod, too. um how it's it's easy
and every team I've been around has
always said we're tough and always
wanted to be physical. Um it's one thing
to say that and think that that's what
you are. It's another thing to sort of
bring it into the process the way they
do. Uh you really get the feeling that
no player gets in here without them
passing that test. And James says
there's certain measurements they have
for it. I kind of visualize it every
time conversation is Tony going, "Are
they tough?"
>> Yeah.
>> You know, so but regardless, that's the
spirit of it. And I'm saying that as a
very positive thing. Hey,
>> let's not forget when we like this guy's
speed that we need him to be playing
physical football for us on Sunday. So,
I think the fact that that is so much in
the forefront of their mind, uh, as
Brian said, it's it has been impressive
around here in what, 13 or 14 months
>> of how it's now easy to see what they're
about on the field when they talk it.
And at the end of last season, teams
started realizing,
I'm not sure fans realized how tough
this team was, but teams playing against
them, uh, they won games at the end of
last year, not just because Trevor was
running for touchdowns with the long
hair, they were out physicing and, uh,
teams were backing down from them a
little bit.
>> It's easy to get on board when there's
no gray, right? When it's black or
white, when you know exactly what the
expectation is, it is easy to get on
board. And when they bring players in
who all know that,
you can just feel it in this building.
It's very hard to translate through a
television camera, but you understand
what they're doing and why they're doing
it.
>> And making that commitment to it, John,
when you talk about it's not always easy
to remain on the you want to be tough,
but okay. Well, we need to make some
picks that maybe aren't.
>> But I love this guy who runs a 4-3.
>> Maybe not a sexy pick, but yeah,
>> but remember, he doesn't bl. And that's
what the draft conversations are about.
Hey, yes, he does these things well, but
then you back up and say, "Yeah, yeah,
but we're going to be running the ball
40% of the plays." And if this receiver
doesn't block, that stuff doesn't work.
And teams can really talk themselves
into guys who aren't what they are, who
aren't what they want.
>> Uh, but I think this team does a great
job of making sure, hey, you know, uh,
remember what we're about before we let
this guy come in here. So, that's our
analysis of at least Duvall DNA for now,
but we also want to touch on the
consensus board because that's been a
big topic on social media over the
weekend. Um, James Gladstone was on the
Ozone podcast this week and he kind of
addressed that issue.
>> I listen to what's being said about
players uh in a very real way. I care
about it. I listen to those in this
building and the people that we have
invited into this building
>> and what their perspective is on these
players. We build consensus internally,
right? And that is leveraged at every
pickpoint. uh our wisdom of the
collective is how we phrase it and right
>> it is what guides our decision- making
and I can tell you that when we get up
uh on the clock we're looking at the
draft board and we see on it our
sentiment and Duvall DNA and those are
the two
>> north stars so to speak and that is a
collective output and ultimately when we
look at the guys that we select we're
not selecting them without some version
of consensus this
>> John. I know that was part of a longer
conversation with him, but it's not like
he's just ignoring everybody else's
thoughts and and analysis. It's just a
matter of not wanting to I know they've
talked a lot about not wanting that
group think, right? They want to think
independently and then come together and
see what everybody's values are and
where there's crossover and where that
meets.
>> Yeah. How much time do we have because I
can go on forever about this, but and I
even told James, maybe we saw it on
that. Um, I didn't do a great job asking
the question, partly because I was so
flumxed with the whole idea of it that I
thought it was ridiculous.
>> But it was such a topic this weekend
that I did want to get his thoughts on
it. Um,
the idea of a of a consensus board that
teams should be paying attention to what
is quote out there.
>> I don't get that at all.
>> Let me clarify this. teams should be
aware of what they believe that other
teams are thinking during the draft so
that you can plot your strategy. Uh a GM
and a GM should never be thinking
what does this website say about this
guy's value. Uh there's a huge
difference in that and uh I I love James
answer. It was what I thought he would
say. you know, their consensus, Brian,
is built on all of the information that
they spend countless hours and countless
equity gathering. It's why they're here.
And uh, you know, so if I ever heard a
GM say, "Hey, you know, drafttech.com
said this guy was a second round pick,
so I rolled the dice and went with it."
Okay, great.
>> Listen, I I had done this is my 32nd
draft. I've never heard the term
collective board. I had never heard the
term consensus board. I I I in in the
over the weekend after the draft I read
it I thought what the hell does that
mean? There's no consensus. You work to
build consensus in your room. But you
there's no consensus around the league.
There's no one shared board that
everyone goes to that it's preposterous.
And you talk about knowing what other
teams are thinking. They've always
worked to know that. They pick up the
phone. They call other scouts. scouts,
not webdraft internet gurus. They go
scouts and they talk to them. They share
information. They get a little
information. They give a little bit of
information. But
it's frustrating because and Mel Kyper
Jr. has to do this, right? I mean, he
has built this industry and everyone has
followed in his footsteps, but his
analysis of the Jaguars draft said,
"Well, I had this guy as a fifth round
pick.
>> Who cares? You're not a general manager.
You're not picking for these teams. And
listen, Mel doesn't care what you think
because he's just chuch-ching
chuch-ching chuch-ching making money.
And God bless him. Good for him. But it
doesn't matter what Dane Bugler or Mel
Kyper or even Pete Prisco, right, who we
love. Their opinions are their opinions
and they don't make decisions here based
on that. So, they thought that Nate
Boracher was a fifth round pick. They
didn't see it in this draft room that
way. And we were just talking about the
Duvall DNA and how dialed in they are on
what's important to them. Once they get
what's important to them, they don't pay
attention to what draft analysts are
saying on ESPN or Jaguars.com.
>> The nice thing about this is over the
course of a couple years,
>> you're going to find out. And that's
really that's always the amazingly
comical thing to me about the draft. And
I struggle with it because I try to give
some, you know, real information when I
write and speak. I don't always do a
great job. That's the effort. With the
draft, it's very, very difficult because
people want to know right now what it
is. And the reality is
>> you don't know.
>> If you're talking about, well, I graded
them this way. Well, okay, great. I when
they drafted Britain Strange and Parker
Washington, Had I been an independent an
analyst, I probably would have said D's
because I hadn't heard of them,
>> right?
>> Well, egg on my face, right? So, that's
what I always try to keep in mind
whenever I look at a draft of, hey, this
is great, but you just don't know. Uh,
the Seahawks famously in 2012 was I won
the Super Bowl
>> with the core of with the core of their
team, a draft class, they got resounding
Fs. Yeah.
>> So, at that point, you should know what
draft grades mean. The draft process by
its nature, Kai, is subjective, right?
It's it's it's an opinion based on
facts. You put data there and and they
come up with their board. But the
result, which we always have said is
three years from now, is very objective.
You can go and see how many games did
they play, how many guys are still on
the roster, what kind of results did
they create. So, we're going from all
this subjective to now a very objective.
At the end of the 2027 season, you go
put a grade on what they did. Yeah,
>> you just can't do it instantly.
>> It's too early to know, but um it will
be interesting to see how it progresses
certainly. And it was a different draft
force around here in Jacksonville, so
that makes it unique in its own self.
Stay with us here on Jagam. We'll tell
you what's coming up the rest of the
week.
Uh welcome back as Jaguars get ready for
the 2026 season. Make your deposits for
your tickets now. It's limited seating,
so the stadium will be open, but the
upper deck is closed. It looks different
every time we come in. There's some
other giant piece of concrete moving in.
They're building the outer concourse.
It's looking really cool. Um, but there
will be less seating. So, make sure you
check out jaguars.com/ickicketing
and get your lock get locked in for your
tickets now so you don't miss any of
those matchups.
>> I think it's going to be kind of cool.
She was like, "Hey, I got this idea.
Let's let Akari, you know, put out some
cups. Let's let her crawl what she
thinks." And I was like, "Whatever."
like I don't really not whatever in a
bad in a way of like I don't care but
like I like sure I like why not and then
I go and play the game and then her
family's in town so they all did it and
I'm watching in the background and then
every time they're like she went to
Jacksonville she went to Jacksonville
she went to Jacksonville and I was like
well since the end of the season I've
been saying Dball is where I want to be
and she went three times and then it was
just like
well I was like God is it's written in
the books I was God never lies he never
does wrong. And I mean, I'm hearing it's
just amazing.
>> Albert Regis, his daughter had a little
ESP, picked out the Jaguars Cup when
given the options of where he wanted to
go. Maybe she likes kitty cats. Not
really sure. Um or maybe there's a
couple videos of that.
>> The irony is versions.
>> The irony is that uh it says in his bio,
grew up a diehard Houston Texans fan.
>> They're converting some fans in the
family, I'm sure.
>> Absolutely. Um such a cool experience.
Obviously, the rookies aren't in this
week, I think. Is it next week rookie
mini camp mini camp next Friday and
Saturday
>> so we'll get them in here. Um a big
class of of undrafted free agents as
well. And what's cool about what they
did last year is we got some really good
contributions out of BJ Green and Danny
Strago who were both undrafted. So
there's that's a group as well that when
we get them in here, we'll get to see
some other new faces that maybe we
hadn't heard of before that could be
contributors.
>> Yeah, there's some guys running back
from Virginia uh and uh offensive tackle
from you. I mean, I was line from UCL
like three guys went to the combine. Uh,
but the combine doesn't always indicate
who the really good guys are. Some of
the guys last year who who were really
good were not guys that you thought
initially. Uh, Stri and Green when you
first looked at the bios probably didn't
translate into being what they were. So,
uh, point being these 18, uh, I think
there's probably four or five guys they
really like who are are very excited
about who could contribute.
>> No grade, but I I I thought it was a
really solid effort and and filling a
lot of spots where you needed
competition, but you also get Caleb
Bransaw and Jayla Mloud back and you
hope to have Wyatt Milm healthy through
training camp. So, I mean, those are
three guys that you kind of add to this
class and say there is a lot of
potential for this team to be better
this year because of young players.
>> Also, if you guys haven't seen it, um,
Zack Dery, who was picked, the edge
player picked in the seventh round was
um, player X for the ESPN article this
year, which is with a blind item they do
about what they think is the most
underrated prospect. So, that's a pretty
interesting story and they have an
update to it now that it's been
revealed. So, that's interesting. You
definitely want to check that out. Um,
we'll be here kind of analyzing
everything and we'll be back with you
again next week. So, have a good one.